
Lab work 1.  Real numbers
Develop a console application in Java.

A function is represented as its Taylor row. Calculate the approximate value of the sum of this infinite series. 
End the calculation when the next summand is modulo less than the given number eps. The type of this number is determined by the following condition:
eps = 10^(-k), where k is a natural number. 
Compare the obtained result with the value calculated through standard functions.
Enter the values of x and k from the keyboard. 
Output the result with three decimal places after the decimal point.


Function: 1/√(1+x)=1-1/2 x+(1*3)/(2*4) x^2-(1*3*5)/(2*4*6) x^3...; x∈(-1, +1)

Description of solution: 
The Calculation_class class contains a getTailor() method that calculates an approximate value of the function 1/sqrt(1+x) using the Taylor series. 
The method uses the eps variable to determine the precision of the calculations. The smaller the value of eps, the more accurate the calculations will be.
The getTailor() method starts by initializing the last, sum, eps, and n variables. It then uses a while loop to calculate an approximate value of the function. 
In each iteration of the loop, the method calls a helper method called getNext(), which calculates the next term in the Taylor series. 
The method then adds this term to the sum variable and increments the value of the n variable. 
The loop continues until the absolute value of the last term in the Taylor series is less than the value of eps.
The Main class contains two methods, getNum() and getNumD(), which read an integer and a double from standard input using a BufferedReader.
These methods are used in the main() method to read values for the variables x and k. 
The method then creates an instance of the Calculation_class class and uses it to calculate an approximate value of the function. Finally, it prints out the results.


Лабораторная работа 1.  Действительные числа
Разработать консольное приложение на Java.

Функция представлена в виде своего ряда Тейлора. Вычислить приближённое значение суммы этого бесконечного ряда. Вычисления заканчивать, когда очередное слагаемое окажется по модулю меньше заданного числа eps. Вид этого числа определяется  следующим условием:
eps = 10^(-k), где k – натуральное число. 
Сравнить полученный результат со значением, вычисленным через стандартные функции.
Значения x и k ввести с клавиатуры. 
Вывод результата осуществить с тремя знаками после десятичной точки.